loveworldtv.co.uk 2019-06-04

# Privacy Policy - LoveWorld TV

Your data is important. It’s important to us, and we understand that it’s important to you. LoveWorld Television is committed to safeguarding your information in line with the latest data protection and privacy laws. We also want to be transparent about what information we collect about you, how we use it, and how you can control what we do with this information.

This privacy policy covers the collection and use of your personal information by us and parties that we authorise, such as our suppliers and subcontractors.

It applies to our services, including the provision of social media and interactive applications, audio visual content, text, photographs, advertising and other services that we offer at [www.loveworldtv.co.uk](https://www.loveworldtv.co.uk/). They also include any of our other websites, applications and/or media platforms that enable you to interact with our programming and/or view our content over a mobile or wi-fi network.

By accessing and using our services, you are agreeing to the terms of this privacy policy and to our Cookie Policy at [www.loveworldtv.co.uk/cookies](https://www.loveworldtv.co.uk/cookies)

We may update this privacy notice and our cookie policy from time to time and we’ll post any changes on our website at [www.loveworldtv.co.uk](https://www.loveworldtv.co.uk/)

In this policy, “We”, “Us” and “Our” means LoveWorld TV.

This privacy notice was last updated on 22 May 2018.

  * Any personal details you knowingly provide us with through forms and our email, such as name, address, telephone number, photographs, etc.
  * In order to effectively process credit or debit card transactions it may be necessary for the bank or card processing agency to verify your personal details for authorisation.
  * Your preferences and use of email updates, recorded by emails we send you (if you select to receive email updates or newsletters).
  * Your IP Address, this is a string of numbers unique to your computer that is recorded by our web server when you request any page or component on the Website. This information is used to monitor your usage of the Website.
  * Data recorded by the Website which allows us to recognise you and your preferred settings, this saves you from re-entering information on return visits to the site. Such data is recorded locally on you computer through the use of cookies. Most browsers can be programmed to reject, or warn you before downloading cookies, information regarding this may be found in your browsers ‘help’ facility.

It’s your responsibility to ensure that any registration data you provide to us is accurate and kept up to date.

We, and our authorised third parties, may use cookies and/or other tools to store and sometimes track information about you. We may also access certain information stored on the devices you use to access our Services. For more details about what cookies are, the cookies we use and how to disable them, please see our Cookie Policy at [www.loveworldtv.co.uk/cookies](https://www.loveworldtv.co.uk/cookies)

We keep your personal information for only as long as necessary, which is longer in some cases than in others. The length of this retention period depends on the purpose for which the data was obtained and its nature. For example:

  * we may need to keep some personal information about you so we can deal with any complaints you might make about the Services we provide to you
  * if you ask us to stop processing your personal information for direct marketing, we need to retain enough information about you to enable us to ensure we stop including you in those direct marketing activities
  * we may need to keep personal information so we can defend possible future legal claims. Unless there’s some other reason for keeping it, personal information will deleted when such a claim could no longer arise (most claims can only be made within 6 years of the event that gave rise to the claim, except for personal injury claims, which must be made within 3 years)
  * we may have a legal or regulatory duty to retain particular personal information for a certain minimum period (for example under Ofcom rules, or under HMRC tax rules)

We and our authorised third parties may use your information in a variety of ways, to:

  * process payments from you to us (where applicable)
  * deal with any complaints or enquiries made by or about you

We’ll only process your personal information where we have legal grounds to do so. Generally, we’ll only process it on the following grounds:

  * you have given consent for the processing. When we rely on consent to process your personal information, you always have the right to withdraw this consent.

We’ll only send you email updates or newsletters if you indicate that you consent (for example by opting in) to receiving such messages.

You always have the right to object to us processing your personal information for the purposes of direct marketing.

To stop receiving email updates or newsletters from us, you can use the ‘unsubscribe’, ‘stop’ or similar facility contained in any such communication. Alternatively, you can email us at [info@loveworldtv.co.uk](mailto:info@loveworldtv.co.uk) stating that you do not wish to receive further communications from us.

We may pass information about you to other parties as follows:

  * to third parties authorised by us and acting on our behalf, such as our employees, contractors, suppliers and/or agents, to administer the Services provided to you. These third parties are only allowed access to your information as needed to perform functions of the Services or to provide services to us. They’re not allowed to use it for any other purpose.
  * We use MailChimp as our marketing automation platform.
  * for communications, where we have your consent to do so.
  * as part of general statistical information about the Services’ user base, sales patterns, traffic volumes and related matters. This information won’t include details from which you could personally be identified.

Any personal information you supply will be treated in accordance with applicable data protection laws including the General Data Protection Regulation (the “GDPR”) and any other applicable or superseding legislation. We are committed to delivering the rights that individuals are entitled to under data protection laws in the UK. These are:

  * the right to request a copy of the personal information we hold about you. To do this, please contact us at [info@loveworldtv.co.uk](mailto:info@loveworldtv.co.uk) making clear that you are requesting a copy of your personal information and including full details of what you require. You may also be required to submit a proof of your identity.
  * the right to object to your personal information being used for direct marketing. Where required we will ensure we obtain your consent before undertaking marketing and you will have the ability to opt out.
  * the right to object to your personal information being processed where the legal basis for the processing is our own legitimate interests as an organisation. We will comply with such a request unless there is a lawful reason for not doing so, such as when we need to continue to process your information to defend a legal claim or if this information is necessary for the ongoing provision of our Services.
  * the right to rectification. You may request that we correct any inaccurate and/or complete any incomplete personal information.
  * the right to withdraw consent. Where we are processing your personal information on the basis that you have given us your consent to do so, you may withdraw your consent at any time.
  * the right of erasure. You may request that we erase your personal information and we will comply, unless there is a lawful reason for not doing so. For example, there may be an overriding legitimate ground for retaining your personal information, such as keeping your payment information for several years to comply with HMRC rules.
  * the right to data portability. In certain circumstances, you may request that we provide your personal information to you in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and have it transferred to another provider of the same or similar services to us. Where this right is applicable, we will comply with such transfer as far as it is technically feasible.
  * the right to lodge a complaint with the supervisory authority. We suggest that you contact us about any questions or if you have a complaint in relation to how we process your personal information. However, you do have the right to contact the relevant supervisory authority directly. To contact the Information Commissioner’s Office in the United Kingdom, please visit the ICO website for instructions.

This privacy notice doesn’t cover companies, services or applications that we don’t own or control, or people that we don’t employ or manage. This includes (without limitation) third party websites or applications/widgets (e.g. from social media platforms such as Facebook or Twitter) that we link.

Nor does it cover advertisers so if you click on an advert and it takes you to an advertiser site, please check their privacy notice.

LoveWorld Limited is registered in England and Wales (registered number 04691981), registered office, Unit 2 Standard Industrial Estate, Henley Road, London, E16 2ES.

The Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) regulates our processing of your personal information. You have the right to lodge a complaint with the ICO. Details of how to contact the ICO can be found on their website at ico.org.uk.

If you wish to contact us about our privacy policy, please email us at [info@loveworldtv.co.uk](mailto:info@loveworldtv.co.uk)
